OK now that we know how to create variables how to initialize them and how to use them within a string
using the variables within our previous code should be very very easy.
And I'll show you why.
First of all I'm going to uncomment these statements because Python is ignoring them now.
And to do that you can manually just remove the hash in front of the lines or just highlight the lines
that you want to uncomment and press control and forward slash.
Now this is done.
If you look at the code here you can see the first part of this function is actually a string.
So it's a sequence of characters enclosed by two quotation marks.
Therefore if we want to replace this with the value that stored in this variable we have to do with
the same way that we did it in our print statement.
So all we have to do here is we have to close the quotation marks the strings and we have to append
or put our variable in the middle of the string like so.
So it's very similar to the way that we're using it in here.
And this print statement again we have to do it in this line.
And same for this line
and that's it.
Now whenever Python runs it's going to replace interface here with the value that we initialize it to
in here.
One more thing that we need to do is use the Neumark.
So I actually modified this code in the previous lecture to show you the difference of using the variable
inside and outside the quotation marks.
So I'll just fix this here.
And we also need to use it in here.
And again all we have to do is just append the code in here.
So I'm removing the.
That's hard coded within the string and then I'm going to append the new Mike to the string.
So as you can see now we're actually using the same concept that we used when we were using the variable
within the print statement and that's why I was saying it's very useful to get into the habit of printing
your variables and using the print function.
Also sometimes it's a good idea if you're running system commands like this.
Maybe you can just print this right here so you can just copy this and use it in a print statement and
make sure that your command is being interpreted by Python the way that you want it to look like.
So I'm going to save this.
And let's run our code and see what happens.
So my current Mac address ends with 6:6.
As you can see here and if we run our program you can see it's giving us a nice print statement and
then if we do if can glance 0 you'll see the MAC address has changed to 7.
Now what's really handy with using the variables is let's say you want to change the MAC address of
a different interface.
Not for land zero you would have had to change the value in all of the commands in here.
And if you have a bigger code than you would have had to went and looked for every single time you use
that value and change it to the new value.
Whereas in our code let's say I want to change the MAC address of 88 0 which is another interface that
I have here.
So if I do if config it to 0 you can see its MAC address ends with 7 7 Actually now.
So let's change the Neumark and make it.
And with 8 8 and run our code.
Now if we do if conflict it is zero again as you can see the MAC address changed to the new value.
So instead of going through the whole code and changing the value for line zero all we have to do is
just change it in here and said that to eat 0.
Same goes for change in the Neumark.
If you had a big code you would have had to look which line of this code change the MAC address instead.
If you have everything here on the top or in one place then it's very easy for you to change it and
not to worry where this variable is used.
All you have to do is just change its value here and then it'll change all over the code.